Guide to the Robert W. Straub Oral History Project 2003-2007
Western Oregon University Archives
- Interviews
  - Sweetland, Monroe, 2004
    Monroe Sweetland, a friend of the Straub family, was an active figure in the Oregon Democratic Party and served for ten years in the Oregon Legislature. A strong advocate for education policy, he later worked for the National Education Association.
    - 1/26/2004
      Formats: 1 Digital8 tape, 1 DVD access copy
      Length: 43:14
    - 3/24/2004
      Length: 1:00:45, 35:31
  - Thomas, Patty Straub, 2005
    Lana Patricia (Patty) Straub, one of the Straubs' daughters, married Jay Thomas. The couple ran a timber operation in Curtin.
    - 10/29/2005
      Length: 1:02:32, 51:07
  - Thomas, Peggy Straub, 8/30/2005
    Margaret (Peggy) Straub, one of Bob and Pat's daughters, married Robin Thomas. The couple have two children, and live in Eugene, Oregon.
    - 8/30/2005
      Length: 1:01:44, 28:15
  - Wyss, Loren, 2005
    Loren Wyss, a close friend of Straub's, was an investment consultant who served on a variety of boards, including the State Board of Education and those for TriMet, 1000 Friends of Oregon, and the Bend Bulletin. He also served as president of the Wyss Foundation, a charitable organization.
    - 11/10/2005
      Length: 1:01:27, 50:45
    - 11/17/2005
      Formats: 1 MiniDV tape, 3 DVD access copies
      Length: 1:01:20
  - Excerpts
    - "Straub OH Board Mtg. Presentation" (Jean Russell; Ken Johnson), 08/2003; VHS (2 copies)
      The tape, compiled by Michael O'Rourke for a Straub Oral History Board meeting presentation, begins with O'Rourke discussing how excited he is to be a part of the project, and giving an update on his progress. It includes excerpts from two early interviews of Jean Russell, who tells an anecdote from her childhood in which the family dog was stolen, and her brothers searched to get the dog back; and of Ken Johnson, discussing the controversy over a fundraiser during Straub's 1964 campaign for treasurer that was raided--as a result of the opposing campaign's reporting--for not having a liquor license. Later on, the tape also includes part of an OPB special about Nixon and Watergate.
    - "Bob Straub Oral History- Presentation, B.S. Archives Board Meeting" (Pat Straub; Barbara Hanneman), 11/2003; MiniDV, DVD, and VHS
      Includes Pat Straub's reminiscences about Bob's first entry into politics and his time as a Lane County Commissioner, as well as Barbara Hanneman's discussion of Bob's frugality; Hanneman shares a story about one of Bob's visits to New York City to sign bonds as State Treasurer, when he visited with her twin daughters, who were attending Columbia, and was tempted into trying to sneak two people through a subway turnstile using only one token.
    - "Governor Straub Archives Project Demo" (Floyd McKay; Jim George; Roger Meier), 4/28/2004; VHS (2 copies); MiniDV
      Includes interview footage of Floyd McKay discussing the Straub family farmhouse, of Jim George recalling meetings with investment bankers on trips to New York City to sign bonds while Straub was State Treasurer, and of Roger Meier discussing the Oregon Investment Council.
    - "Straub Archives Video Excerpts" (Neil Goldschmidt; Mike Straub; Patty Straub Thomas), 11/2005; DVD
    - "Straub Archives Oral History Excerpt" (Ken Johnson and Janet McLennan; Fred Miller), 4/26/2006
      Formats: 1 DVD with video recording, online streaming video and .pdf of transcription.
      The interview, conducted at McLennan's Portland home, discusses the Nestucca Spit highway issue, and particularly Straub's role in opposing the highway construction.